

Mobile - +64 22 072 5530 Email - derbyshire@outlook.co.nz Portfolio - codyderbyshire.com

# **Career Objective**

I'm Cody and I'm on the search for front-end and design roles. I'm an outgoing and driven young professional who loves a challenge both in and out of the workplace. I'm driven to achieve the best I can and that is reflected in my work. I enjoy solo work as well as any chance for collaboration in a team.

# **Skills Summary**

# **Problem Solving**

While working at Scale Studios as a Designer and Manufacturer and during my studies I have learned how to efficiently tackle problems as part of my workflow. While working on Evil Dead Rise I designed a bleeding-elevator button rig that was not only time-sensitive but also restrained by budget. By developing a system using stacked laser-cut acrylic I was able to prototype and build the rig quickly and cheaply.

### Leadership

Led a 3 person team to build an interactive website for Toi Whakaari's FWID 2020, encompassing a fun user-experience and a complete visual identity. As a team I spearheaded the implementation of a workflow to take in artist-submitted imagery and implement it into the site as part of a homogenous identity. I thoroughly enjoyed working as part of a diverse team of creatives. The festival site was scaled to include 100+ events and presentations, was deployed on time and was one of the highlights of my time at Toi Whakaari.

#### Learning

I am a very fast learner who excels at learning-by-doing. Both Yoobee College and Developers Institute employ a self-directing approach to learning which I very much enjoy. During my time at Developers Institute I have been working on learning different React libraries such as Framer Motion and Shadcnui in my spare time to not only improve my front-end skills but keep up with the current industry-used tools.

# **Experience Summary**

| In-house Designer + Manufacturer at Scale Studios | 2020 - 2022 |
|---|-------------|
| Freelance Designer                                | 2018 - 2021 |

#### **Education**

| Diploma in Web Development and Design at Developers Institute        | 2023 – present |
|--|----------------|
| NZ Certificate in Information Technology (Level 5) at Yoobee College | 2018 - 2020    |
| Bachelor of Design at Toi Whakaari NZ Drama School                   | 2022           |
| Diploma of Costume Design at Melbourne Polytechnic                   | 2017           |

## **Detailed Experience**

In-house Designer + Manufacturer at Scale Studios

2020 - 2022

I was the in-house designer and manufacturer responsible for creating film props and set-dresssing elements for films and television shows.

Skills / Tools Illustrator, Photoshop, Fusion 360, Rhino, Blender, 3D printer, lasercutter, CNC mill Achievements Worked on Avatar 2, Rings of Power, X, Pearl, and Evil Dead Rise

#### Freelance Designer

I have worked as a freelance designer on the side, creating but not limited to websites, business cards, branding, posters, pamphlets, invitations, and user experiences.

Skills / Tools

Achievements

Created branding and marketing for the Manifest designer showcase, built festival website and user experience for FWID 2020



Mobile - +64 22 072 5530 Email - derbyshire@outlook.co.nz Portfolio - codyderbyshire.com

### **Technical Skills**

### **Digital Design**

I have many years of experience and really enjoy digital design. While working at Scale Studios I presented an entire re-brand of the studio's identity which was well-received. I have maintained a freelance design presence alongside my studies, which has helped me grow and learn as a designer by adjusting to a client's needs and developing deliverables that make an impression.

### Front-End Development

Over the last 2 years I have been learning front-end development and finding tools that enable me to create the impact that I want to make. I really enjoy the fast-paced environment of ever-changing and developing practices that combine left and right-brain thinking. I currently work within the MERN stack, which I find to satisfy the needs I have in front-end, with an ever-growing exploration into emerging practices like Astro and Matter.js.

# 3D Modelling

As part of my work at Scale Studios and in my own time I have developed a very good grasp of 3D modelling in programs like Fusion 360 for CAD to CAM workflows in a professional context for prop and set design, as well as furniture design as a hobby. In addition to this I have learned Blender for use in creating models for 3D printing as well as implementation into developing skills in WebGL and ThreeJS as part of my front-end practice.

#### **Interests**

Outside of a professional context, I love tinkering with physical projects like building keyboards and computers or hobby woodworking and furniture restoration, as well as digital projects like building my personal brand and learning new front-end libraries to deploy in my portfolio. I love a good fantasy book and strategy / puzzle games.

References available upon request.